Based on a true story.
Out of Africa is a history, romance, drama film directed by Sydney Pollack.
Tells the life story of Danish author Karen Blixen, who at the beginning of the
20th century moved to Africa to build a new life for herself.
The film is based on her 1937 autobiographical novel.
Denys George Finch Hatton, played by Robert Redford.
Karen Christence Dinesen Blixen, played by Meryl Streep.
Baron Bror Blixen/Baron Hans Blixen, played by Klaus Maria Brandauer.
Berkeley Cole, played by Michael Kitchen.
Farah, played by Malick Bowens.
Lord Delamere, played by Michael Gough.
Out of Africa is a 1985 American epic romantic drama film directed and produced
by Sydney Pollack, and starring Meryl Streep and Robert Redford.
The film is based loosely on the 1937 autobiographical book Out of Africa written by Isak Dinesen (the pseudonym of Danish
author Karen Blixen), with additional material from Dinesen's 1960 book Shadows on the Grass and other sources.
The book was adapted into a screenplay by Kurt Luedtke,
and this screenplay was filmed in 1984.
Streep played Karen Blixen, Redford played Denys Finch Hatton, and
Klaus Maria Brandauer played Baron Bror Blixen.
Others in the film include Michael Kitchen as Berkeley Cole, Malick Bowens as Farah, Stephen Kinyanjui as the Chief,
Michael Gough as Lord Delamere, Suzanna Hamilton as Felicity, and the model and actress Iman as Mariammo.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
It was also a commercial success and won seven Academy Awards
including Best Picture and Best Director for Pollack.
The film explores themes of farm, infidelity, africa, plantation, safari.
The tone is emotional.